-[car engine revving]
-[dramatic music]
Oh, man, let's hope this works!
Hope what works?
-Awesome!
-Whoo-hoo!
Not bad for something
I didn't have any time
to test out, right?
Sure, but a head's up
would have been nice!
Oh did I not mention
this thing splits apart?
-Negatory.
-Sorry.
I mean, why'd you think we each
had our own little cockpits?
Just thought it looked cool.
Come on, we gotta catch
up to that Pace Dragon!
[dramatic music continues]
[crowd cheering]
Yeah, baby!
Do I put on the
sweetest games or what?
What-what?
The Merge was
caused by Master Wu.
-That can't be true!
-But it is.
The Ninja's precious Master
Wu was the very person
who caused the Merge.
He is solely responsible for
your parents going missing,
and every other catastrophic
effect of the Merge.
No way.
Master Wu was a wise man.
He wouldn't have
caused all that.
[chuckles] Arin, you still see
the world as a tiny child does.
Yeah, right.
To you, the Ninja
are always good,
and I am always the villain.
Okay, I agree with that.
[sighs] Real life doesn't
work like that.
There is light in the darkness,
and darkness in the light.
So I'm supposed to believe
you're some kinda hero?
I've done harsh things.
But always in the service
of reversing the Merge.
That's really been your
goal this whole time?
Undoing the Merge?
Only by re-separating
the Merged Lands
will we be able to save
them from each other.
It must be done.
And the process could bring
back all of those who were lost.
I...
I don't trust you.
I don't need you to
believe me now, Arin.
Because I know the day will
come when you see I am right.
Let's hope you do
before it's too late.
You mean, we're free to go?
You always were.
[Ras laughing]
♪ Lost in the unknown
so much to see ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja for what's right ♪
[flames whooshing]
-[dramatic music]
-[engines revving]
I don't see the Pace
Dragon anywhere.
Don't lose hope.
I need a better vantage point.
Found it!
Is it close?
I'd say it's the
opposite of close.
Pour on the speed!
[dramatic music continues]
Ha!
Pace this, dragon!
Come on, we can pass it
inside this tunnel...
-Uh oh!
-What "Uh oh?"
Don't just say "Uh oh!"
There's been a cave-in!
There's no other way through!
So what are you suggesting?
Driving right into this wall?
-Great idea, Nya!
-What?
[Nya] That was not an idea!
I hope this works...
If it doesn't, we'll
find out real quick.
I was guessing this thing
would be strong
enough when combined.
Master Wu did say,
"Only unity can save us."
Do you think he
was talking about
driving through a rock wall?
-Probably not.
-Come on!
We gotta beat that dragon!
Hold onto your masks!
[dramatic music continues]
[all gasping]
What the what?
They did it!
That was ultra stang-zoot!
I hereby gotta say,
the Ninja are officially
still in the games!
[gentle music]
Thanks, Riyu.
I know I should talk to Lloyd,
but he'll never
believe his Uncle Wu
could've done
something that bad.
-[Riyu chirping]
-Yeah, Ras is probably lying.
But what if it's
even partly true?
Frak trusts him, and he was
always a great judge of people.
And Ras is right
about one thing.
I'm not the ninja I should be.
You really think Sora
faked my object Spinjitzu
and didn't tell me?
Yeah. Yeah, Ras is probably
lying about that, too.
I hope.
[Kai] Riyu?
Can you hear me?
-We need help.
-Hey, buddy.
Thought we were having
a moment here, but okay.
You do you.
[dramatic music]
Come on, Euphrasia...
[yelling]
[crowd cheering]
-Whoa!
-Close one!
Remember, whoever
knocks their opponent
off their platform
first equals: winner!
Cloud Monk!
What do your precious
scrolls say about this match?
The Writers of Destiny
no longer believe
our words dictate all outcomes.
We also use our actions
to help decide our fate!
Well, my actions
will decide yours!
We have a winner!
[Zeatrix laughs]
The Elemental Power of Wind!
A perfect compliment
to my powers!
See how I handled that monk?
That's nothing
compared to the destiny
I'm gonna write for you, Ras.
[Ras growls]
[dramatic music]
Uh-oh! A cloud of knock-out gas
so thick you could chew on it!
[dramatic music continues]
[crowd gasps]
Nokt wins!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Security!
Stop or you're disqualified!
[Nokt chuckles]
Told you it would be
no problem, sister.
Sister?
One, two, three.
Hey Frak.
Hey, man! Sorry I haven't
been around much,
my Master put me on an
intense training regiment.
I haven't even seen many games.
Frak, why didn't you tell
me Ras was your master?
Why? Do you know him?
Yeah. He's an enemy
to the Ninja.
Ras hunted dragons for Imperium,
he captured the Cloud Kingdom-
Uh, maybe we're talking about
different guy named Ras?
Because he's been
nothing but good to me.
Just tell me, have you used
one of those Wolf Masks
with the gong?
I wish!
Shatterspin is amazing!
But my Master says first I
need to get my skills up.
That's why I've been
training so hard.
Don't do it ever!
The Gong actually shatters
the goodness inside you.
You're joking, right?
Those masks will make
you more powerful,
but they corrupt you.
Poison you.
Ras only cares about power,
no matter what the cost.
That doesn't sound right.
Everything Ras taught me
to do has built me up.
Look, I'll show you.
Follow my movements.
Ras says everyone
spends too much time
trying to find harmony.
But you can't passively wait
for the world to harmonize...
So you must take from
life what you need.
Well, I do feel
like sometimes life
is just dragging me along.
Hyah!
I've been able to do a wonky
form of Spinjitzu for a while.
Hyah! But I haven't
progressed at all.
My master says we must
force the progress we need.
Force the world to work
the way you want it to.
Power through!
Whoa!
I did it. I did it!
-A real Spinjitzu tornado!
-Nice!
You have no idea how long
I've been trying to do that!
That felt amazing!
That felt right!
And all it took was a little bit
of my Master Ras's teachings.
[phone chiming]
Speaking of which,
my Master wants me
to come to the plaza.
Maybe I'm competing today!
Let's go!
[Arin sighs]
[dramatic music]
Lloyd looks absolutely
green with envy
at Mr. Pale's
light-bending inviso-power!
[grunting
Ow!
When did you learn to do that?
You're not the only one
who's been training!
We gotta lot of catching
up to do, buddy,
after I bring home that trophy!
Now this is just
getting annoying.
[crowd cheering]
It was impossible not
to see that victory!
Lloyd wins!
Well-played, Greenie.
Well-played.
Wow, since you've
always been invisible,
I've never actually
seen your face before.
That's an interesting beard.
Yeah, you try shaving
with invisible skin.
Now Lloyd has the
powers of Mr. Pale.
Care to prove it?
-[crowd cheering]
-Where is he?
Zero time to chillax,
'cause the next two
competitors are up!
First, he's the ninja
that flirts with dirt,
Cole, Elemental Master of Earth!
-Huh.
-Really.
And his competitor: The
snake who shakes and breaks!
He's Frak, Elemental
Master of Quake!
[crowd cheering]
Why is Arin with him?
Hey, Arin...
I'm here!
It's an honor to
compete with you, Cole!
-Sorry I was late, Roby!
-No problem.
No one loves a dramatic
entrance more than me!
This event puts
the hurt in hurdle!
To win, you gotta be the
first to ring the bell!
You ring, you
cling onto victory.
Stang-Zoot!
[bell rings]
[dramatic music]
[grunting]
Oh no!
Is it over for Cole?
[dramatic music continues]
[grunting]
Can't control metal!
So now you believe me that
Frak is on Ras's team?
I told you I
wouldn't lie to you.
-Are you sure about that?
-Huh?
Someone told me that during
the Blood Moon Ritual,
I didn't knock out Ras
with my object Spinjitzu.
That you used your power
to make me think I did.
-[crashing]
-[crowd gasping]
I...
I did.
I'm sorry.
Nya was about to be sent
into the Nether Space.
You were our only hope and
I couldn't let you fail.
And you were so frustrated when
you got demoted in training,
I just wanted you to have a win.
So not even my best friend
thought I could do it on my own.
No, it's not like that, I...
It's like this whole thing
is built for Frak's powers.
Photo finish! But this photo
has a clear winner.
Frak is victorious!
[laughing]
You have no idea
how exciting it is
to have met you, Cole.
You've always been
an inspiration to me.
Uh, thanks?
I can't believe it!
It's like when I used to
pretend to be a Ninja,
but it's a real power!
Woo-hoo!
You fought hard, Cole.
You should be proud.
Not to be that guy,
but did this game seem
weighted against us?
Yes. And remember how we
didn't get invitations
in the first place?
I'm having some suspicions.
We have some time
before the next game,
but we need to keep
our skills sharp.
Every time we lose,
Ras gets closer to whatever
his evil endgame is.
How did you pull
out that landing?
I've got the elemental power
of balance now, remember?
Sora, I can tell
you're distracted.
And if you're distracted,
you'll never achieve Spinjitzu.
I know, I know. I just, have a
lot on my mind right now.
Are you sure you should've
told the Ninja brat
all of that, Lord Ras?
Information can be power.
And information can be poison.
I omitted some of my intentions,
but everything I
told him was true.
And that truth will
poison his mind.
And that poison will
spread to the other Ninja.
And drive them all apart.
Exactly.
Because they are the only threat
to my main goal in
this tournament:
gaining control of all
the Elemental Powers.
That is the only way I can
create the Dragon Icons I need.
Is a Dragon Icon how you lured
and trapped that Source
Dragon under Imperium?
Yes. Without the proper Icons,
summoning Source
Dragons is impossible.
So we cannot suffer
any more losses
at the hands of the Ninja,
like Jay Walker did.
We must win by any
means necessary.
Of course, Master.
And we're back!
Every game, the competition
gets competitiver,
the intensity gets intenser,
and fun gets funner!
And that's not gonna stop
now with our next battle:
You know her, you love her.
Nya!
[crowd cheering]
Versus the mysterious man of
few words and fewer fears.
Nokt!
Where's your brother?
Not here to cheer?
Or what of that
other useless Ninja?
The one you supposedly love?
He's just trying to get
into your head, Nya.
Well I'm gonna get into
his head with my fists!
Wyldfyre, your
anger's not helping.
It's helping me stay angry!
This battle is ramping
up to be legendary!
During this fight, three...
Count 'em, one, two, three.
Holographic gems
will appear randomly.
The goal: whoever
gets the most, wins!
Yeah! Go Nya!
[dramatic music]
[both grunting]
One gem for Nokt, and
a big fat zip for Nya!
But the game's just started!
Anything could happen!
I was expecting the other
member of your family.
You think Kai was tough?
You've never seen
me when I'm mad.
[dramatic music continues]
Hyah!
And just like that,
it's a tie game!
Whoot-Whoot-Stang-the-Zoot!
Get your Rising
Dragon ready, Nya,
he's gonna Shatterspin!
Yes! Destroy him so hard, Nya!
But not angrily.
A friendly destroy.
-[dramatic music continues]
-[both grunting]
[crowd cheering]
And Nokt is victorious!
What an amazing,
incredible battle!
What? But the gem disappeared
right before I was gonna get it!
Sorry! Rules of the game!
Okay, I know this
doesn't look good.
Yeah, it looks super terrible.
-Thanks, Wyldfyre.
-You're welcome.
But Ninja never quit, right?
Up next: Sora, Elemental
Master of Tech and Balance!
Versus Cinder, Elemental
Master of Smoke and now Heat!
[both grunting]
I've been waiting for a rematch
since the Wyldness, girl.
This isn't just a test
of Elemental Skills.
It's a challenge of the mind!
The competitors must
solve these puzzles,
including a swing
over a fiery pit!
You were right.
Sora admitted she
used her powers
and let me think
I did it myself.
You'll see I'm right about
a great many things, Arin.
Jay Walker worked at
the Administration.
I think he knows where my
parents disappeared to.
Any information Jay
Walker has, I also have.
[bell dinging]
[both grunting]
Only a few ways
these could work.
You always fall for that trick!
You think I'm not prepared?
[gong ringing]
There are like a gazillion
patterns to this one!
Ugh.
Let's try something simple.
1-1-1-1-1.
-[both grunting]
-[Cinder yells]
Sora wins!
[all cheering]
Huh?
What are you?
Where are you taking me?
There's nothing here.
If I had my powers, I'd
make an earth bridge
and follow you to
whatever is out there...
Another Monastery?
[dramatic closing music]